<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.novelia.space/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://www.novelia.space/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-08-09T17:02:07+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Novelia Space</title><subtitle>Welcome to Novelia Space! </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Research</title><link href="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research"/><published>2024-08-09T16:59:24+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-09T16:59:24+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/research</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/research/"><![CDATA[<p>Here I take notes of passing thoughts on research.</p> <h2 id="what-should-be-a-good-aim-when-doing-research">What should be a good aim when doing research?</h2> <p>Getting papers accepted vs. getting citations vs. generating research impact, what is the ultimate goal?</p> <p>From a discussion with more senior researchers I am getting a feeling that none of the abovementioned goals are ultimate. Instead, for them the ultimate goal is very simple: to enjoy the research process.</p> <p>All the aims listed in the paragraph should be a “why-not” addition to the enjoyment of research itself.</p> <h2 id="knowledge-research-skills-and-intuition">Knowledge, Research Skills and Intuition</h2> <p>Knowledge sets the foundation for every scholarly pursuit, research skills make you a qualified scholar, while intuition decides how far you can go.</p> <h2 id="a-scholarly-investment-in-effort">A Scholarly Investment in Effort</h2> <p>Let’s consider a simplified scenario. Suppose that the sum of our available time for work throughout our life is a fixed number. You are free to allocate the time to whatever you see fit. What would be your schedule if you want to produce world-class scientific research?</p> <p>For me, I would definitely like to reserve some quality time for the cultivation of intuitions. Acquirement of knowledge is certainly important, but a mindless bump into the vast universe of knowledge only gets us lost in it. We simply do not have the time to learn everything. We need guidances. Quality guidances. And that is where intuitions come into the picture.</p> <h2 id="theories-serve-to-predict">Theories Serve to Predict?</h2> <p>It seems to me that people generally favor theories that predicts better. Indeed, how can a theory be useful and remembered if it cannot predict anything?</p> <p>The ability to predict is oftentimes more credited compared to the completeness of theory itself. What are we seeking, utility or theory itself?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here I take notes of passing thoughts on research.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introvert</title><link href="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/introvert/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introvert"/><published>2024-08-09T16:50:55+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-09T16:50:55+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/introvert</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/introvert/"><![CDATA[<p>I am an introvert. I am proud of being an introvert.</p> <p>PS: I really need to understand much more people (than I currently have) to produce meaningful generalizations for psychological matters. You are welcome to correct me if anything below does not look right.</p> <h2 id="introverts-and-extroverts">Introverts and Extroverts</h2> <p>It is usually easy to distinguish between introverts and extroverts by appearance, by looking at how willing and comfortable they are when interacting with other people. Introverts are usually labeled “quiet” and “shy”; they like to spend time alone, and tend to get exhausted from socializing.</p> <p>From my <strong>very limited</strong> observation of people around me, I speculate a more fundamental definition of introverts.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Introverts are those who spend more time thinking about themselves rather than about other people.
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The judge-by-appearance definition and my definition of introverts might have slight discrepancies, but I believe (for now) that they mostly refer to the same group of people.</p> <h2 id="features-of-introverts">Features of introverts</h2> <p>Before a certain level of intellectual maturity, introverts can be sensitive to external feedback, both positive and negative. Positive feedbacks will bring more motivation, while negative feedbacks will hurt more deeply as well.</p> <p>Because of it, introverts are often put in disadvantageous positions during elementary education, at least in China. There is a rumored comtempt chain regarding Chinese teachers: university professor &gt; high school teacher &gt; middle school teacher &gt; primary school teacher &gt; kindergarten teacher. So, not every primary school teacher in China gets a PhD from prestigious universities, and things <em>will</em> get ugly when your teacher is pissed off. Unfortunately, introverts take more damage from it.</p> <p>I am, nevertheless, not arguing that elementary education is unfair or something, because introverts do have their unique powers, for instance, the inclination to get down to thinking.</p> <h2 id="guide-to-becoming-friends-with-an-introvert">Guide to becoming friends with an introvert</h2> <p>Birds of a feather flock together. Generally introverts get along with each other well, because they naturally know and respect what it takes to be an introvert.</p> <p>Extroverts often misunderstand introverts, and therefore I think it would be good if I summarize some common misconceptions here.</p> <ol> <li>Introverts are <strong>NOT</strong> to be confused with people with autism. We do socialize when we want to or when we feel necessary. We can talk a whole lot.</li> <li>But when we socialize (esp. with strangers), we drain mental power quickly. In an ice-breaking party for instance, typical extroverts cannot wait to get to know every one, while introverts will get mentally exhausted after getting in touch with a few.</li> <li>Introverts may need to take a break from social activities once in a while, not because we are unhappy, not because we hate anyone, but because we are mentally tired and need to recover.</li> <li>Similarly, when introverts talk little, it does not mean we do not like you. Sometimes we enjoy your presence more than words.</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am an introvert.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Truth</title><link href="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/truth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Truth"/><published>2024-08-02T14:11:54+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-02T14:11:54+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/truth/"><![CDATA[<p>Humans have lives just long enough to know that what we usually refer to as truth is ephemeral. Yet truth is something we cling on to, something we cherish so much as not to get lost in our journey forward.</p> <h2 id="the-relativity-of-truth">The Relativity of Truth</h2> <p>Experience has led me to conclude that truth is most of the time relative, but not completely, so as not to fall into the pitfall of absolute relativism.</p> <p>Absolute relativism is inherently contradictory: if “nothing can be absolute”, then the truth value of the assertion can not be absolute either. On the other hand, if it is not the case that “nothing can be absolute”, we still face the question about whether the statement is false (i.e., absolute truth exists) or an <em>indeterminate</em> third value (i.e., absolute truth may exist or not).</p> <p>For the purpose of my writing, it is not productive to ask whether absolute objective truth exists. For now, I will put the question aside and focus on a more “pointed” version of relativity. While much flexibility exists for the “truthfulness” of any statement, there are trends and inclinations in it.</p> <h2 id="truth-and-value-judgement">Truth and Value Judgement</h2> <p>What is good, and what is bad? What is right, and what is wrong?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humans have lives just long enough to know that what we usually refer to as truth is ephemeral.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Death</title><link href="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/death/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Death"/><published>2024-08-02T14:11:54+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-02T14:11:54+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/death</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2024/death/"><![CDATA[<p>Much as we fear death, we have to learn to embrace it. Not because we have to accept the fact that All Men Must Die. Nor because of the need to prepare ourselves for it. But because it is from death, and death only, that anything significant receives its value.</p> <h2 id="death-is-everything-eternality-is-nothingness">Death is everything. Eternality is nothingness.</h2> <p>All of us dream of having eternal lives. But if one day, humans are really granted eternal life, they will not want to live eternally. If one is forced to live eternally, it will be a curse rather than blessing.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Much as we fear death, we have to learn to embrace it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Definition</title><link href="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/definition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Definition"/><published>2023-12-10T10:40:39+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-10T10:40:39+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/definition</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/definition/"><![CDATA[<p>Definitions are natural derivatives of the categorization efforts of human, a necessary component of reason.</p> <p>Perhaps we should begin the discussion by making a number of definitions.</p> <p>How to define literature? How to define music?</p> <p>Those definitions are notoriously hard to give, and has only been obscurely outlined by scholars as not completely objective or subjective.</p> <p>Borrowing from <a href="truth.md">my truth theory</a> objects of consistency also exist for definitions. Every definition must be understood and evaluated with pertinence to its scope.</p> <p>I do not, for instance, think that the infamous 4’33 is invariably music to everyone. The significance of 4’33 should rather been put against a cultural background, an apex of carefully organized, tonal music. It is undeniable that 4’33 has made such a big impact on musicians with regard to the extends of music, but that reason along does not justify its empty, non-music nature.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Definitions are natural derivatives of the categorization efforts of human, a necessary component of reason.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self</title><link href="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/self/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self"/><published>2023-12-06T17:07:59+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-06T17:07:59+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/self</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/self/"><![CDATA[<p>Who am I? The fundamental question of self is an inevitable topic of thought for every human. In those stages of life when we are more naive, content, or motivated, we tend to think lightly of it. The true import of the question only becomes known when one falls into the more negative part of the realm of emotions. Most, if not all, of the major depressions in our life can be reducible to a thwarted attempt at defining self.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who am I? The fundamental question of self is an inevitable topic of thought for every human.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Novelia</title><link href="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/novelia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Novelia"/><published>2023-09-16T09:46:11+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-16T09:46:11+00:00</updated><id>https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/novelia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.novelia.space/blog/2023/novelia/"><![CDATA[<p>Novelia is the name of the site. What else do you expect, huh.</p> <h2 id="novelia-space-is-a-space-of-concepts">Novelia Space is a space of concepts</h2> <p>Believe it or not, my envisioning of Novelia Space originates from the word <em>novel</em>. By then it was Project Novelia, a Interiors project that aims to help me read more novels. Well, apparently it failed.</p> <p>Meanwhile, I was having an idea. To take a snapshot of my current system of thought, so that I can reference and compare to it later, and, if anyone who has lost their way stumbles upon it, provide some inspiration for them. That is the ultimate goal of what turns out to be Novelia Space.</p> <p>Then I meditated for quite some time on its organization. How can a complex system of thought be flattened into one or several linear stream of words? In computer science we call that process serialization. So, one quick way of serializing ideas is by putting a structured index at the beginning (which we usually refer to as the ‘contents’ section), and we will end up with a <em>book</em>, with different chapters covering various aspects of thought.</p> <p>I initially followed this approach, but it was not long that I found out that I lacked both the proficiency and perseverance to handle the many intricate interwoven threads that constitute several fundamental conceptions. My system is far from complete and internal severances and contraditions are everywhere. Simply put, I am not ready for a book.</p> <p>Afterwards, I begin to seek alternative ways of serializing ideas. One day, when I was on a business trip, an idea occurred to me. Insteading of flattening ideas into a linear sequence while somehow preserving their relations, why not keep the original interconnected nature of ideas and record each of them as-is? Thing can be organized in relation to those basic building blocks of ideas: <em>concepts</em>. Better still, owing to the flexibility of the digital text formats we have today, we can easily connect concepts via links, effectively producing a <em>concept space</em>.</p> <p>And yes, Novelia Space is organized around concepts.</p> <h2 id="novelia-space-is-very-personal">Novelia Space is very personal</h2> <p>Novelia Space is not Wikipedia or Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Everything in Novelia Space is personal. I do not strive to achieve complete objectivity. I just faithfully record my thoughts.</p> <p>That being said, the ideas I record in Novelia Space are often my firmest convictions. I have always tried, to the best of my ability, to maintain the quality of my beliefs, and to (hopefully) provide nourishment to the minds who need it.</p> <hr/> <p>Anyways, welcome to Novelia Space!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Novelia is the name of the site.]]></summary></entry></feed>